

# Michael

### Backend Software Developer

12 December 1987



California



949-228-0695



michael hor vath 87@gmail.com

### About me –

Originally from Kansas, Michael has lived in eight states and two countries. Michael enjoys climbing, running trails then napping, howling with his guitar, and anything else he can do outdoors. He's been coding for about five years now, but he's been exploring since the day he could walk – perhaps even earlier.

# Python VIM Whiteboarding Unix Figuring it out

(\*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

## beliefs

Continual growth is key to enjoyment of life; challenge begets growth.

Passion is a must.

Software = Poetry + Math

## education

2006-2011 B.A. cum laude

University of Kansas

Psychology and Statistics

2002-2006 High school, 4.0 GPA

Shawnee Mission East HS

Extras: Diving, Soccer, Choir, Science Olympics

### awards

1997	Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania Assoc. of Private Schools
1998	Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania Assoc. of Private Schools
1999	Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania Assoc. of Private Schools
2000	Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania Assoc. of Private Schools
2001	Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania Assoc. of Private Schools
2005	Science Olympiad State Champion, Chemistry
2006	CalTech Signature Award, Excellence in Science and Mathematics
2016	Heart and Soul Award, Lawrence Ultimate Frisbee League

### experience

2018 - Now Software Engineer

Fluxergy, LLC

- Cloud-based automatic upload, processing, and report generation of clinical test output. (Django and MySQL).
- Platform for creation, tracking, and real-tim display of manufacturing floor processes. (Flask and PostGRES).
- Implemented R&D computer vision solutions to ISO 13485 standards. (Python, c++, NumPy, openCV).
- Real-time monitoring and processing of time-series data and production metrics. (PowerBI, ELK).
- Study planning and execution to pass ISO 13485 regression validation requirements.

2017 - 2018 Software Engineer

Embrace Healthwear, LLC

Developed activity classification models with biometric data to map physical therapy research to procedural findings.

2016 - 2017 Personal Project

Elixir/Machine Learning

Built a neural net constructor in Elixir, in order to better understand the fundamentals of machine learning.

## skills

2018-2020 Python, Django, Flask, PHP, MySQL, PostGRES, Docker, LaTex, docker-compose, Git, Cloud resources (Azure and AWS), Database design, Elasticsearch/Kibana, PowerBI, c++, TensorFlow, R, LISREL

2010-2020 Program evaluation, technical liaison, public speaking, regression analysis, ANOVA, MANOVA, optimization, structural equation modeling, business intelligence

### other information

Michael used to work in construction and property management. He's found some odd overlap between his previous career and his current one, mostly in visualizing interdepent systems and the value of elbow grease (not to mention the horror of opening up someone else's beloved home to find that the whole thing is tied together with (more or less) strings). He'd love to find a home where he can continue to grow and be challenged by exciting new projects on a regular basis.